Warner Family Papers, 1884-1921 Ms 48
Fairfield Museum and History Center
Warner Family Papers, 1884-1921
Ms 48
Fairfield Museum and History Center
0.33 Linear feet (1 box; 3 folders)
Warner family
Warner, Lucien C. (Lucien Calvin), 1841-1925
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
Doctors Ira DeVer Warner (1840-1913) and Lucien Calvin Warner (1841-1925) were brothers from Chenango County, New York. They took their medical training in New York State and eventually started a corset factory in Bridgeport, CT in 1876 called Warner Brothers.
Lucien C. Warner lived in New York City and was president of Warner Chemical Co. He financed the Conservatory of Music at Oberlin College in 1884 and was heavily involved with the YMCA. Other family members in this collection were associated with the Warner Corset Co. For more detail, see the genealogical chart in the collection.
Scope and Contents note
The collection is housed in one box and primarily consists of letters to Lucien C. Warner. Many of them are from prominent people including Rutherford B. Hayes, Grover Cleveland and Andrew Carnegie. Folder C holds a scrapbook of newspaper clippings (1887-1917) about the Warner family.
Carnegie, Andrew, 1835-1919; Cleveland, Frances Folsom, 1864-1947; Cleveland, Grover, 1837-1908; Hayes, Rutherford Birchard, 1822-1893; Oberlin College. Conservatory of Music.; Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1839-1937; Warner Brother's Company.; Warner Chemical Co.; Warner, Ira DeVer, 1840-1913; Correspondence.; Scrapbooks.
- Letters, 1886-1910; Folder A; 38 items
  - Letters from:
    - Lucieh Thompson Warner (Golden, CO), 1888; 2 items
    - Noah H. Osborne (McGrawville, NY), 1886; 11 items
  - Letters to Dr. Lucien C. Warner
    - Letters re: Oberlin College's Conservatory of Music, 1882-1889; 9 items
    - S. Smith & Son (jewelers), 1886-1887; 2 items
    - Rutherford B. Hayes, 1888
    - unknown, Governor's Island, NY, 1890
    - Grover Cleveland, 1891, 1905; 2 items
    - Andrew Carnegie, 1893
    - Helen Miller Gould, 1899, 1902, n.d.; 3 items
    - International Committee of Young Men's Christian Association, 1898
    - John D. Rockefeller, 1905, 1910; 2 items
    - Louis C. Tiffany, 1908
    - Mary (Mrs. L. T. Warner), n.d.
  - To Noah Osborne from Benjamin Harrison, 1888
- Letters and Miscellaneous, 1880-1921; Folder B; 21 items
  - Letters to Mrs. Lucien Warner
    - Frances F. Cleveland
    - Helen Miller Gould, 1904
  - Letters to Mr. and Mrs. Warner
    - John D. Rockefeller, 1918
    - Lucien Warner, 1918
    - "Nellie" Converse Seeley, 1918
    - G. Frederick Wright, 1918
  - Cards to Dr. and Mrs. Lucien C. Warner, 4 items
  - Letters to Mrs. Philip B. Warner
    - Joseph Hopkins with card, 1921; 2 items
    - Nellie M. L. Jenkins, 1921
  - Letters from Lucien C. Warner
    - John D. Rockefeller, 1910
    - Brother, 1910
    - Children, 1913
  - Letters unidentified, 1882
  - Program of dedication of Warner Hall, Oberlin College, 1884
  - School certificate to Eva Follett, 1880
  - Miscellaneous, n.d.; 2 items
- Scrapbook of Newspaper Clippings, 1887-1917; Folder C